Guide to the Miriam Frank Oral Histories on Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, Transgender, and Queer Activists in the Labor Movement OH.039
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Vince Quackenbush, Apr 7, 1995 (Box 4, Cassette 34-35, Box 1, Box 8, Audiocassette OH_039_034, OH_039_035)
  This interview took place in San Francisco, CA. Quackenbush grew up in a New York State Democratic Party family in Albany. After college, he took a state government job and was a rank and file member of the Civil Service Employees union. He moved to San Francisco in 1980, took a sales job at Sears and joined Local 1100 Retail Clerks. His interview covers the topics of upstate NY gay community politics, family reactions, gay community and life in department store workplace, formation of Lesbian and Gay Labor Alliance, unionization and picketing of Castro community businesses, Gay Freedom Day parades, anti-concession contract campaign 1993, union drive San Francisco AIDS Foundation SEIU Local 798, Gay/labor Prop 84 anti-La Rouche campaign 1986, gay contract language, gay community politics, SEIU hospital workers Local 250 strike support, Building Service Eployees Local 14, International Federation of Professional and Technical Engineers Local 21 and comparison with NYC gay/labor politics.
- Kim Ramsey, Jul 14, 1995 (Box 1, Box 6, Cassette 102-103, Box 9, Audiocassette OH_039_102, OH_039_103)
  This interview took place in Seattle. Ramsey was raised in Dearborn, Michigan to parents who were doctors with anti-racist values. Her interview covers the topics of Quaker boarding school, Alabama cajuns at summer job clothing sweatshops 1960's, Ypsilanti welding job at brother's machine tool shop, sexism at machine shops, being hired at General Electric jet engine plant IUE #1002 1984, inspiration of union activism, SWP, campaign vice president 1002, SLUw leadership seminars, Gloria Johnson at Evergreen State Women's Summer school gay/lesbian seminar 1990, confronting homphobia, conservatism, union reform, international solidarity, Hormel P-9 strike, red-baiting late 1980's, GE industrial policy and international trade, IUE internal politics, Staff Washington Public Employees Association, IUE discrimination resolution at IUE regional conference, and gay baiting as a mask for racism.
- Teresa Rankin, Jun 9, 1995 (Box 1, Box 6, Cassette 81-82, Box 7, Audiocassette OH_039_081, OH_039_082)
  This interview took place in Washington D.C. Rankin was raised in rural Virigina in a rural Southern Baptist mill town. Her interview touches on the topics of segregation and civil rights 1960's, college and radical influence, coming out in the women's movement early 1970's, DC lesbian/feminist scene, JP Stevens boycott staff Baltimore 1976-1981, separating lesbian community life from union work, ACTWU mentors and social life, SLUW older lesbian scene, pressure of union life, union/lesbian identity, AFL-CIO IUD and TWU staff, union organizers and male culture, coordinating 1983 Civil Rights March on Washington and gay question, NEA staff 1986, gay/lesbian AFL-CIO reception March on Washington 1987, gay men teachers 1990's, 1993 March and AFL-CIO and NEA receptions, and DC Lambda Labor.
- Amanda Ream, Nov 10, 2008 (Box 4, Cassette 124-125, Box 2, Box 9, Audiocassette OH_039_124, OH_039_125)
- Ron Rebant, Apr 27, 1995 (Box 1, Box 5, Cassette 60, Box 7, Audiocassette OH_039_060)
  This interview took place in East Pointe (Detroit). Rebant was raised in Warren, and his father was a union steward at Chrysler. Rebant was in a straight marriage for 8 years and had two kids before he came out. His interview discusses the topics of estrangment and divorce, the court ordering against kids' visit when his partner is present, his ex-wife's outing campaign to supervisor at work and to entire family, changes in technology, his desire to have his partner Ed on his health plan, meeting other Chrysler (non-union) gay workers, Ron Woods present at Ed/Ron's wedding, Chrysler redneck work culture, gossip, women co-workers who were visible lesbians.
  NOTE: Ron's partner Ed Preby makes occassional comments.
- Scott Reed, Jul 13, 1995 (Box 2, Box 6, Cassette 99, Box 9, Audiocassette OH_039_099)
  This interview took place in Seattle. Reed was raised in an Air Force family and was a member of the newly unionized mental health agency Bremerton UFCW #381 1988. His interview discusses the topics of bisexual identity, crisis union involvement/client repsonsibility, strike threat, controversy union history/ULP charge, gay identity in the workplace, HERE #8 staff job, rapport with gay banquet workers, coping with overt sexual harassment from older straight official, Local 8 contingent Seattle Gay Pride 1990, staff SEIU/1199 Northwest, queer caucus, organizing OutFront Labor Coalition, fighting anti-gay initiatives 608/610, union marches Gay Pride, Hands off Washington coalition, COPe convention 1993, organizer burnout quit 1199, training gig IFPTE #17 and proposing job share with lesbian friend 1994-1995.
- Rosalie Regal, Feb 14, 1995 (Box 3, Box 2, Box 4, Cassette 8-9, Box 8, Audiocassette OH_039_08, OH_039_009)
  An alternate spelling of this interviewee's last name may be "Riegel." This interview took place in Brooklyn, NY. Regal's interview covers topics such as coming out in the lesbian bar world in the late 1950's, house parties, outlaw life, alcoholism, lesbian working class jobs, butch dressing, marriage, lesbian pulp literature, Daughters of Bilitis, importance of feminist influences, sobriety in the 1970's, Women in the Trades, her entry into the telephone crafts at age 47, rank and file movements, local politics in CWA 1101, her activity in the Bell Ringer, cameraderie and pressure, sexual harrassment, racism, lesbian identity in the workplace, changing technologies, job transfers and gener discrimination grievance.
- Bill Roberts, May 19, 1995; cuid36288 (Box 5, Cassette 72-73, Box 2, Box 7, Audiocassette OH_039_072, OH_039_073)
  This interview took place in Glendale (Los Angeles). Roberts was raised in Philadelphia in a Navy family during World War II. He was trained in the Metropolitan Opera ballet and was married at age 17 with multiple theatrical union memberships. His interview covers the topics of stagework culture and queer feelings, bisexual living, street and porno world California, double life, alcoholism, show business, being a choreographer with showgirls in Las Vegas, fighting NBC/Disney on issue of dance floor safety, sponsorship by George Meany to learn labor law, AGVA rep early 1970's, leadership of lengthy widely publicized Disneyland strike, picket line actions, OPEIU Local 30 project, sobriety 1972, father/son coming out to each other, living iwth AIDS since 1987, friendship with his wife, leaving AGVA, Gwen Newton union mentor, teaching labor arbitration UCLA, confronting homophobia at union functions, March on Washington AFL-CIO reception 1993, activity in HIV/AIDS community "Fightback" classes at community centers, and newspaper column "Fightback" as bridge of union politics and HIV/AIDS community.
  Duration: 85 minutes; digitized recording is in two parts, part "A" (23 minutes) and part "B" (62 minutes).
- Faith Robinson, Apr 30, 1995 (Box 2, Box 5, Cassette 68-69, Box 7, Audiocassette OH_039_068, OH_039_069)
  This interview took place in Detroit. Robinson was raised in Ohio in a church missionary family. She converted to Judaism and was married with two daughters. She was a W. Michigan NOW officer and came out in the mid-1970's. She was divorced and moved to Detroit receiving a job in the Orkan exterminating business. Her interview covers the topics of the Detroit lesbian and Jewish scene, her difficult family past, acquiring blue-collar work skills, her job as a line technician at Michigan Bell, lesbian baiting and harassment while on probation, CWA Local 4100, controversy in CLUW Non-Traditional Work Committee, her promotion to splicer, coming out on the job, Detroit CLUW, president Detroit NOW, CLUW activism in mid-1980's, camparison of the two organizations and issues of coming out in CLUW.
- Linda Romero, Jun 12, 1995; cuid36289 (Box 6, Cassette 85-86, Box 2, Box 7, Audiocassette OH_039_085, OH_039_086)
  This interview took place in Washington D.C. Although herself not a lesbian, Romero was an SEIU Education Coordinator dealing primarily with lesbian/gay issues. Her interview includes the topics of being a school bus guard then driver AFSCME, union campaign Gibralter, SEMTA driver Local 1564 ATU steward 1978-1990, sexism and racism at the workplace, contract language on "sexual predilection," occupational injury, women's leadership training U/M Labor Institute summer schools, hired SEIU 1990, bisexual first husband, friendships with gay people San Francisco Castro scene, her own bisexuality in the 1970's, social justice training anti-homophobia, DC Lambda Labor, economic/moral angle on domestic partner benefits, the future of anti-homphobia work outside Lavendar Caucus influence, and the holy scriptures.
  Duration: 95 minutes; digitized interview is in two parts, part "A" (32 minutes) and part "B" (63 minutes).
- Sue Schurman, Jul 18, 2001 (Box 4, Cassette 122-123, Box 2, Box Shared Tamiment 086, Audiocassette not numbered)
  This interview took place in Washington D.C.
- Rita Shaw, Jul 12, 1995 (Box 2, Box 6, Cassette 95-98, Box 9, Audiocassette OH_039_095, OH_039_096, OH_039_097, OH_039_098)
  This interview took place in Seattle, Washington.
  Tape #095: Shaw was raised in the Bronx/Brooklyn to East European Orthodox Jewish immigrants. Her father was active in the Furrier's Union in the 1930's. This tape covers the topics of boarding school lesbian subculture, rebellion against religion and arranged marriage, Zionism, Communist Party youth politics, Teen Trotskyite SWP/YSA activism, interracial dates, her marriage to NMY Seaman Ed Shaw, streetfights CP/SWP, anti-red fight NMU, anti-military activism late 1940's, her move to LA, supermarket clerk RCLA, party split cochran and more to Detroit early 1950's.
  Tape #096: Detroit: rebuilding SWP red scare and recession, banquet waitress jobs/union, electoral campaigns, abortion network Dr. Ed Keemer jailed 1950's, previous abortions, raising kids, Cuba tour and Fair Play for Cuba, move to NYC, marriage conflict, NYC schools activism, SWP male chauvinism, separation 1960's, Seattle feminist scene NOW, abortion rights and anti-war movements.
  Tape #097: Rita as an unemployed single mother, NOW activism, SWP conflicts, landmark cases reproductive rights, celibacy, feminism and marriage, karate and weapons mid-1970's, Seattle CLUW, ERA coalition, sexuality and identity, relationship with partner Joan Sandler, issues with her teenage kids, and SWP industrial union campaigns.
  Tape #098: Railroad job BRAC (now TCIU) since 1979, non-traditional women railroad crafts, lesbian workers, union democracy, technology and job losses early 1980's, 32/40 work week campaign, Lodge President Peter Palpano then red-baited her, CLUW support red-baiting phase, SWP mass expulsions 1984, Central America coalition CLUW support, SWP opposition and CP ally 1985 and union social events.
- Van Sheets, Jun 8, 1995 (Box 6, Cassette 74-75, Box 2, Box 7, Audiocassette OH_039_074, OH_039_075)
  This interview took place in Washington D.C. Sheets had a Republican upbringing in Washington D.C. This interview covers the topics of AFSCME staff 1982, gay identity and union work, feminism, culture of union headquarters/field, AFSCME gay/lesbian politics and leadership, AFL-CIO headquarters gay receptions 1987 and 1993, tasks of DC Lambda Labor, unionizing non-profit gay organizations, comparison of Whitman Walker and NYC GMHC campaigns, partner's death 1989, being HIV positive for ten years, confronting homophobia, AFSCME lesbians, "gaydar," anti-gay rights campaigns, headquarter party drag performance and AFSCME lesbian/gay advisory committee work of regional councils.
- Irving Smith, Aug 9, 1999 (Box 4, Cassette 124-125, Box 2, Box 9, Audiocassette OH_039_139, OH_039_140)
- Sidney Sushman, Mar 22, 1995 (Box 2, Box 4, Cassette 17-18, Box 8, Audiocassette OH_039_017, OH_039_018)
  A pseudonym for this interviewee may be "Sylvia Sidney." This interview took place in Boston, MA. Sushman was a drag and vaudeville performer known as Sylvia Sidney "The Bitch of Boston" and was greatly popular in the nightclub and gay bar scene of the 1950's and 1960's. Sushman joined the Hotel Waiters Local 34 in the early 1960's. This interview covers the topics of life in drag, after hours nightclub performances, union parties, picket duty in drag, rank and file participation, changes in union administation in the 1980's, Social Security, and the Sequins for 1981 Solidarity Day rally in Washington DC.
- Sal Rosselli, Apr 13, 1995 (Box 2, Box 5, Cassette 55, Box 7, Audiocassette OH_039_055)
  This interview took place in Oakland, CA. Rosselli was raised in a union family in Albany, NY. He was expelled from Catholic college for anti-ROTC organizing and was involved in the Catholic Worker movement in the Lower East Side of NYC. He moved to California in the early 1970's. His interview discusses the topics of VISTA rural Indiana, community college politics during pre-med school, his job as a janitor and involvement of Local 9 Service Employees, theater janitors strike, Alice B Toklas Democratic Club, first openly gay delegate on the San Francisco Labor Council, homphobia and allies, SEIU Local 250 AIDS education, Local 9 strike and gay community theater boycott during first run of "Making Love" in the early 1980's, president "Alice," Democratic Convention, field rep Local 250 and Kaiser-Permanente strike, election and gay baiting 1987-1988, work of AIDS committee, SEIU Lavendar Caucuses, and SEIU internal politics.
- Keith Truett, Apr 27, 1995 (Box 2, Box 5, Cassette 58-59, Box 7, Audiocassette OH_039_058, OH_039_059)
  This interview took place in Ypsilanti (Detroit). Truett was raised in Dearborn in a UAW Local 600 family. He worked in the same auto parts shop as both of his parents and brother all of whom were accepting of his gayness. His interview covers the topics of family life and support of union struggles, gay men in plant and gay community, his mother's work with HIV positive workers, gay clique and gossip, other workers' awareness, visible butch lesbian co-workers, gay families and divorces in his family, gays in his neighborhood, his desire to follow his mother as Local 600 benefit rep, coming out to co-workers, AIDS, harassment of Ron Woods and the plant as community.
- Martha Voland, Jul 16,2009; cuid36290 (Box 3)
- Kurt Vorndran, Jun 13, 1995 (Box 2, Box 6, Cassette 89-90, Box 7, Audiocassette OH_039_089, OH_039_090)
  This interview took place in Washington D.C. Vorndran was raised in rural Wisconsin to a storekeeper/farmer family. His interview covers the topics of progressivism, coming out late 1970's, national gay rights March 1979, political activism, Common Cause, DC amendment organizing, gay/lesbian Democratic club early 1980's, raising gay consciousness among allies, social issues and cultural conservatism, AFL-CIO Full Employment campaign, National council Senior Citizens late 1980's, comparison of national gay rights AFL-CIO receptions 1987 and 1993, DC Lambda Labor, assistant director of Legislation and Political Action CLUW, gay rights in IUE, union gay role models were Bill Olwell and Tom Kahn.
- Bailey T. Walker Jr., Jun 14, 1995 (Box 2, Box 6, Cassette 91-92, Box 9, Audiocassette OH_039_091, OH_039_092)
  This interview took place in Washington D.C. Walker was raised in the suburbs of Richmond, VA in a military family. His interview discusses the topics of Catholic progressivism, Dominican vows, being ordained a priest at St. Vincent in NYC, gay/religious moral conflicts, gay friends on AFSCME organizing staff Florida, leaving the Dominicans, transfer to DC AFSCME headquarters Education Department, homophobia and gay identity in regions and headquarters, AFSCME gay/lesbian activists Vic Basile (DC), Tom Sadnicki and Barry Friedman (Chicago), Atlantic City convention resolution on gay rights spoken for by Secretary Treasurer Wm. Lucy 1982, HQ staff and diversity training, racial tensions, gay/union work of Tom and Barry Council 31, church/union hierarchies and ethics, and domestic strains and supports.
- Howard Wallace, Apr 8, 1995 (Box 2, Box 5, Cassette 40-43, Box 8, Audiocassette OH_039_040, OH_039_041, OH_039_042, OH_039_043)
  This interview took place in San Francisco, CA.
  Tape #040: Wallace was raised in Worcester, Ma and Denver, CO. Topics include memories of youth during World War II, sickliness, gay feelings, liberal ideas and friends, McCarthyism, "silent generation." University of Denver NAACP electoral work, Students for Democratic Action, United World Federalists, clash with parents, closet existence, suicidal thoughts, and his Socialist Workers Party contacts of the late 1950's.
  Tape #041: Denver SDA screening of "Salt of the Earth," joined SWP, contact with Communist Party, civil rights support, Fair Play for Cuba, closet danger in gay life, homophobic remark Farrell Dobbs, closet affair SWP comrade, cruising and bars, gay sublimination and politics early 1960's, thoughts on Bayard Rustin and James Baldwin, Committee Against Police Brutality, organizing successes and New Left anti-war movement, GI work, moves to San Francisco, Teamster job Local 856, anti-war electoral politics demonstrations late 1960's, SWP anti-war labor organizing and gay issues early 1970's.
  Tape #042: San Francisco gay/hippy scene, anti-war organizing, coming out in movement and influence of lesbian question in NOW 1971, bar world, gay liberation, drifting away from SWP, Maoists in Revolutionary Gay Men's Union, job at peanut factory early 1970's, start of Bay Area Gay Liberation, popularity of BAGL, Harvey Milk's populism, Board of Education campaign 1975, Coors boycott, Teamster Local 888. Allan Baird's work with gay community, brewery workers, national boycott organizer and AFL-CIO work 1980's.
  Tape #043: Coors campaign and lawsuit, gay community work and mass protests in BAGL, leftist splits, placement by Baird as first openly gay beer truck driver Teamsters Local 888, gay identity and Teamsters, AFL-CIO convention mid-1970's, clashes with Milk over Farmworkers grape boycott support, BAGL and building gay/labor consensus for city worker support mid-1970's, DC gay march and AFL-CIO headquarter reception 1987, recognition in SF labor movement, Local 250 Service Employees and work with Sal Rosselli of Theater Janitors Service Employees Local 9, their strike and gay community theater boycott first run of "Making Love."
  NOTE: Howard Wallace's work is also mentioned in interviews with Gary Dotterman, Tom Ammiano, Vince Quackenbush, Leslie Manning, Nancy Wohlforth, Walter Johnson, Allan Baird, Hank Wilson, and Sal Rosselli.
- Karen Wheeler, Mar 26, 1995 (Box 2, Box 4, Cassette 29, Box 8, Audiocassette OH_039_029)
  This interview took place in Boston, MA. Wheeler grew up in Connecticut, spent her teenage years in South Carolina as a "tomboy/nerd" and came out in Boston in 1973. Her interview covers the topics of lesbian bars/sports scene, her 1976 welder apprentice at Quincy Shipyard Local 5 Shipbuilders, left organizations, women union members' democracy issues, non-traditional work, lesbian workplace invisibility after-work culture, age, ethnic, racial and gender issues, asbestos, Boston City Hospital Service Employees Local 285, integration of lesbian and union life, gay/lesbian hospital workers, GALLAN and Fenway Clinic benefit, harassment, workplace romances and domestic partner benefits.
- Hank Wilson, Apr 12, 1995 (Box 2, Box 5, Cassette 53-54, Box 7, Audiocassette OH_039_053, OH_039_054)
  This interview took place in San Francisco, CA. Wilson was raised in Sacramento and was educated at UCLA and University of Wisconsin. His interview covers the topics of VISTA, anti-war activism, FBI harassment, his move to San Francisco in the early 1970's, Bay Area Gay Liberation, street organizing Castro, politics and Left, Board of Education anti-discrimination policy work with Tom Ammiano, parent support of gay teachers, lobbying, teachers coming out, Gay Teachers Coalition work with black community, Gay Democratic Club, Florida Save our Children, Briggs inititative, Larry Burner openly gay teacher in Healdsburg late 1970's, Gay Freedom Day visibility, youth suicide prevention, his 17 years of homeless work at the Ambassador Hotel and development of AIDS outreach.
- Nancy Wohlforth, Apr 11, 1995 (Box 2, Box 5, Cassette 48-49, Box 7, Audiocassette OH_039_048, OH_039_049)
  This interview took place in San Francisco, CA. Wohlforth was raised in Milwaukee in a union family affiliated with AFSCME. Her interview covers the topics of socialist values, student/worker alliance 1968, feminism, socialist group (Workers League), Socialist Workers Party, VISTA, NYC anti-war work, SWP, Coors, gay community politics, gay/union coalition work, domestic partner benefits, VISTA welfare rights sit-ins, Textile Workers JP Stevens campaign, SWP Steelworkers insurgency and Lordstown Autoworkers, Office and Professional Local 3 union politics, Gay Freedom Day, gay indentity in OPEIU, CLUW and NOW in the early 1980's, clerical jobs, her election to Vice President of Local 3 as open lesbian, baiting, gay themes in Local 3 organizing campaigns, gay/lesbian presence in OPEIU, and support from union feminists.
- Nancy Wohlforth, Jun 18, 2006 (Box 4, Cassette 118-119, Box 9, Audiocassette OH_039_118, OH_039_119)
  This interview took place in Maryland.
- Ron Woods, Apr 27, 1995 (Box 2, Box 5, Cassette 56-57, Box 7, Audiocassette OH_039_056, OH_039_057)
  This interview took place in Huntington Woods (Detroit). Woods was raised in a Detroit suburb in a construction union family. He was a member of Local 412 UAW. His interview covers the topics of coming out to his family, working overtime at Chrysler, details of mobilizing grass roots coalition and demonstrations against Cracker Barrel in autumn of 1991, zaps and corporate campaign tactics, press coverage leading to public exposure, his 4 year apprenticeship as an auto eletrician from 1986-1990, shop culture, homphobic factory scene, Cracker Barrel news stories and reactions, ostracism, harassment, death threats, his transfer to a new worksite in August, UAW solidarity civil rights story 1993, standing up to his manager, co-worker respect, campaigning for UAW 1995 Constitutional Convention delegate and being baited by his opponent.